PRASHANT MURARKA

E-mail: prashant.murarka07@gmail.com

(M)-+91-9099937333



PROFILE

An Astute result oriented Manager with 11 Years Experience in the field of Logistics, Supply Chain, Warehouse, Transportation management and Operations. Responsible for delivery of products, detailing drivers for routes, distance and destination. Receiving appliances into the warehouse, stock control of warehouse, maintaining records of deliveries and drivers hours. Planned, supervised, and monitored operations of the manufacturing facility, provided supervision in operations functions including budgeting and forecasting, cost reduction, site inspections, quality assurance, customer service, and continuous process improvement

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Ability to manage multiple assigned responsibilities in high pressure environments with tight deadlines
- Excellent written, verbal, listening, communicating, and negotiating skills coupled with ability to comfortably and confidently present to all levels within the enterprise.
- Good time management & organizational skills ability to plan and prioritize.
- Ability to work across multiple functional organizations and levels in a multicultural and global/matrix environment.
- Diligent attention to details and ability to work under pressure.
- Good Analytical skills and willing to learn.
- Flexibility to take any type of responsibilities.
- Ability to work effectively in a team environment.
- Problem Solving and Decision making.
- Vendor Management and Warehouse Management

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

PowerDrive Bearings Private Limited

Transportation Manager - Logistics, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

May 2013 - Present

- Handling shipments of Bearings, Pulleys and Waste Water treatment parts from China, Europe, ISC (Indian Sub-Continent) Russia and USA.
- Distribution and dispatch of goods locally and nationally through trucks and couriers within given time frame with utmost accuracy.

- Set operations policies and standards, including determination of safety procedures for the handling of goods and ensure compliance with government regulations, company procedures and customer requirements.
- Proactively monitors, records, analyses, and reports on all air and sea import / export, provides results and contribute towards continuous improvement to prevent potential issues.
- Maintain continuous coordination and interaction with planning, production, dispatch, sales and accounts teams to ensure a smooth flow of end to end operational process.
- Ongoing process quality review, root cause for defects, coordinating of process changes with operations, identifying and developing solutions to problems that are not immediately evident in existing systems.
- Negotiates, evaluates, manage and maintain cost with 3PL partners, couriers and trucking companies to control budget and implements most favourable rate quotations for organization.
- Responsible for the accuracy of invoices, bills of ladings, shipping statements, customs documentation and its management. Exposure to MEIS Licence.
- Tracking and getting shipments clear for GST refunds and fulfilling BRC procedure.
- Ensures documents are completed and updated in a timely and efficient manner.
- Preparation of bi-weekly reports comprising shipments details, aging statement, cost statement and remittances of all.
- Direct coordination with custom brokers to ensure continued compliance of origin and destination regulations in a cost effective manner.
- Receive and track purchase orders (P.O.s) from Importers/Overseas offices for pending air and ocean shipments, monitoring delivery schedules too.
- Retrieve shipment details, handle all documentation for cargo release and data entry for each shipment.
- Conducts classification of goods based on information provided by company for United States.
- Daily tracking, tracing and follow-up required to ensure timely and efficient movement of cargo; identify incidents and ensures resolution of incidents.
- Every day manage multiple areas with multiple priorities, coordinate with intercompany cross functions globally.
- Establishing and maintaining good contacts with all national and international carriers, constantly looking for ways to save or avoid transportation costs.
- Ensures a transparent overview of the cost structure through cost analysis, rate administration and maintenance of the database.
- Responsible for evaluating and improving the processes in the areas of transportation, supply chain, logistics and warehouse.
- Arranging local and overseas remittances timely for suppliers, forwarders, custom brokers and transporters.
- Internationally and nationally, consolidate all methods and modes of Transportation (Air, Ground, Ocean, FTL, LTL, and Courier) with all Transport Carriers.
- Physical Stock audit in warehouses, audit of invoices related to all types of shipments.

Shree Rajlaxmi Logistics Private Limited (Guj).

Senior Executive, Ahmedabad, Gujarat June 2009 - April 2013

- Carried out feasibility study of Proposed Project of Company for Residential and Commercial Complex.
- Facilitating in purchase of Warehouses for long term Investment.
- Material handling and warehouse management of building materials.
- Shaped an extensive research on 'Cash and Carry Concept'.

Ravi Kapoor & Associates. C.S. Firm

Executive, Ahmedabad, Gujarat February 2008 - April 2009

- E-filing of Forms related to Incorporation of Company, Balance Sheet, Profit & Loss Account, Appointment of Director/ Managing Director and Compliance Certificate
- Conducted Searches at office of Registrar of the Companies (ROC), Ahmedabad for preparation of Search Report.
- Preparation of MoM of Board of Directors, Annual General Meeting of Shareholders and Extra Ordinary General Meetings.

EDUCATION

Bachelors – Commerce | Gujarat University

2007

CERTIFICATION

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt | KPMG

2018

COMPUTER SKILLS

SAP B1 and MS Office.

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English, Hindi and Gujarati.

I solemnly declare that all the above information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.